And here we are in JupyterLab for the last time, and we are looking here at day five, the last day
유피터랩에 온 건 이번이 마지막이에요 5일째를 보고 있어요 프로그램
of the last week, week eight of the program.
마지막 주 마지막 날, 8주째죠
And we start with the beautiful beginning line import Gradio as GR, which you know what a great fan
GR로 그라디오를 가져오는 아름다운 장면으로 시작해요 제가 그라디오의 열성
I am of Gradio, so I was considering using Streamlit instead.
팬이라 스트림릿으로 할까 생각 중이에요
This time you'll see in my repo I have some other example projects in Streamlit.
이번에는 압류에서 보실 수 있는데, 간소화의 다른 예제 프로젝트들이 있어요
Um, but I figured there's, there's uh, so much, there's great things about Gradio and Streamlit
하지만 그래디오와 스트림리츠에는 좋은 점이 많아요 전체적으로 그래디오에
and all in all, I think I would double down on Gradio.
더 집중하고 싶어요
And so there's no point in, in confusing you with showing you different things that you don't need
그러니 불필요한 걸 보여줘서 혼란스럽게 할 필요가 없죠 전부
because it's all in gradio.
안정적이니까요
So there we go.
자, 됐어요
Uh, with that, we, uh, um, import the deal agent framework and that.
그렇게 해서 거래 에이전트 프레임워크를 수입하죠
So we basically import in here the whole of the thing we were looking at before.
기본적으로 여기서 전에 봤던 모든 걸 불러오는 거죠
And you remember, you can just instantiate this and and call run to set the thing off and we'll import
기억하세요 이걸 인스턴스화하고 실행을 호출해 시작하세요 기회와 거래를
opportunity and deal.
불러올게요
So now as we have talked about I think briefly we covered this, but somewhat in passing in the past
간단히 다뤘던 것 같은데 과거에는 그레이디오에 두 가지 수준의 세부 사항이 있었죠 높은
that Gradio has these two different levels of detail, a high level API and a low level, a bit like
수준의 API와 낮은 수준이요 H깅페이스가 파이프라인과 토큰라이저와
Huggingface has the pipelines and then the Tokenizers and models.
모델을 가진 것처럼요
Gradio has great interface, which is its high level API for quickly building an interface, and it's
그레이디오는 인터페이스가 훌륭합니다 인터페이스를 빠르게 구축하기 위한 상위 레벨 API입니다 단일 함수나 입력, 출력이
really simple to get up and running if you've got like a single function, some inputs and outputs,
있다면 get up 실행이 정말 간단합니다 팝업 창을 열고
and you want it to pop up, you can just use great interface and its cousin, great chat interface that
싶다면 훌륭한 인터페이스와 그 사촌인 채팅 인터페이스를 이용하면 됩니다 물론 우리가
of course we've used to great success.
아주 성공적으로 사용했죠
Um, but the interface is a wonderful way to get up and running.
인터페이스는 get과 실행에 훌륭한 방법이에요
The lower level API is called GR dot blocks, and GR blocks gives you an ability to construct your user
하위 레벨 API는 GR.블록스라고 합니다 GR블록스는 보다 정교하게 사용자 인터페이스를
interface with with some more finesse.
만들 수 있게 해주죠
Um, and you say with roadblocks as and then you can call it anything you want.
바리케이드도 있고 원하는 대로 부를 수 있어요
I say as you are right here, and then you say UI dot launch instead of interface dot launch in-browser
여기 있는 그대로라고 하고 UI.Clow라고 해요 인터페이스 대신요 시작 .in-browser
dot equals true.
.=true
Just means it's going to, uh, throw up a new screen as soon as we run this, rather than it being
그냥 링크가 아니라 이걸 실행하자마자 새 스크린이 나온다는
just a link.
뜻이죠
Um, so that's convenient to know.
알아서 다행이네요
Um, and you can, you can give it a title of the window that's going to come up.
앞으로 나올 창의 이름을 붙일 수도 있어요
Fill width is true is worth knowing.
필 너비는 참은 알 가치가 있어요
If you don't set that, then gradient puts big margins on either side of the window, which sometimes
그걸 설정하지 않으면 창문 양쪽의 마진이 크게 남아요 그게 필요할 때도
is what you want.
있죠
But but often, particularly with the kinds of UIs we're going to be building, we want to use every
하지만 종종, 특히 우리가 만들 UI의 종류에 있어서 가능한 모든 픽셀을
possible pixel.
사용하고 싶어하죠
So fill width is true means that it fills the whole width.
필링 너비는 참이란 너비 전체를 채운다는 뜻이죠
So then there's this construct that you get used to, which uh, um, again, we have come across this
그리고 여러분이 익숙해질 만한 개념이 있는데 다시 말하지만 이건 몇 번 다뤘던 개념이에요.
now a couple of times.
Get it.
But you say with grow and then you put each row of your user interface and you break your user interface
get을 하고 사용자 인터페이스를 각각의 행에 놓고 사용자 인터페이스를 이런
into rows like this.
행으로 나누면 되죠
And in each of these context manager, each of these pieces, you can put a bunch of different UI widgets.
각각의 컨텍스트 관리자 각각의 조각들에 다양한 UI 위젯을 놓을 수 있어요
Um, and then somewhat confusingly, you can also have with column, which is saying within a row.
그리고 좀 혼란스러운 건 Column도 있어요 행 안에 있다고 하는 거죠
I would then like to break things into columns.
물건을 열로 쪼개고 싶어요
And we'll see that in a moment.
잠시 후에 보실 거예요
Another it is worth knowing a pro tip is that you can't have with geo column at the top level.
전문가로서 알아야 할 또 다른 팁은 지오 열은 최상위 레벨에서 가질 수 없다는 거예요
You have to start with zero and then you can have columns and rows, uh, nested I think as deep as
0에서 시작해야 해요 그런 다음 열과 행을 중첩할 수 있죠 그 안에서 원하는
you want within that.
만큼 깊이요
But the top level one has to be rows because Gradio is built to imagine a typical scrollable window.
하지만 최상위 레벨 1은 열로 되어 있어야 합니다 그래디오는 전형적인 스크롤 가능한 창을 상상하도록 만들어졌거든요
Okay, so I am beginning with Geo Row, and I'm just going to put a markdown a heading here.
좋아요, 지오 Row로 시작할게요 마크다운을 입력하죠 여기다가요
And when you use GR dot markdown which gives you a markdown field which I know we've used a bunch of
GR. 마크다운을 쓸 때 마크다운 필드를 제공하죠 지금 많이 사용했어요
times now, you can also put in straight up HTML in there, which is what I do to have some centered
HTML을 바로 넣을 수도 있어요 중앙에 큰 텍스트를 넣기 위해 제가 하는 거죠
The price is right.
가격이 적당해요
And then I put like something below that as well.
그 아래에도 뭔가를 Put처럼 했어요
And let's see that running.
실행해 보죠
I just execute this cell and up comes the window.
이 감방을 실행하면 창문이 열리죠
And it's pretty vanilla at the moment.
지금은 아주 밋밋해요
The price is right.
가격이 적당해요
It's got a heading.
방향이 있어요
You can see that this is a row and that's another row.
이게 행이고 저게 또 다른 행이죠
And there we have it.
다 됐어요
That is simple enough.
아주 간단하죠
We'll close that.
닫을게요
Come back here.
이리 와요
And uh, now we can we can do a little bit more.
이제 비트 더 넣을 수 있어요
So what we're going to do now is add another row.
이제 행을 하나 더 추가할 거예요
And this row is going to contain a data frame, a GR data frame, which is basically a table.
이 행은 기본적으로 테이블인 GR 데이터 프레임을 포함하고 있어요
It's like a think of it like a spreadsheet a little embedded spreadsheet on our screen.
스프레드시트를 생각해 보세요 스크린에 스프레드시트를 끼워 넣는 거죠
And you tell it what headers you want description, price estimate, discount URL, uh, and uh, wrap
헤더에 대해 설명, 가격 추정, 디스카운트 URL 그리고 랩은 엑셀이나
is a bit like in Excel or in Google Sheets.
구글 시츠에 있는 것과 비슷해요.
It's saying that I want to wrap within any cell the column widths which are relative.
상대적인 셀 너비 내에서 래핑하고 싶다고 말하고 있어요
So you can say that I want the first one to be four times as large as the others.
첫 번째 것은 다른 것의 4배로 만들라고 할 수 있죠
How many rows, how many columns, and the height if you want it to have a fixed height.
행의 개수, 열의 개수 고정된 높이를 원한다면 높이를 정하죠
And some of these are optional.
어떤 건 선택 사항이에요
Um, and then, uh, what I'm doing is I'm calling something called UI dot load, which looks like many
UI.Dload라는 걸 호출하고 있어요 그러디오 기능처럼
of the gradio functions.
보이죠
You'll see a very consistent pattern across Gradio, where you say the function takes the name of a
그라디오에 걸쳐 일관된 패턴이 보일 겁니다 함수가 함수의 이름을 취한다고 할
function.
때요
In our case, get table inputs and outputs.
이 경우에는 테이블 입력과 출력을 get으로 하고요
And that's how you hook up a function you're providing to this particular user interface.
이 사용자 인터페이스에 제공하는 함수를 연결하는 방법이죠
And what we're saying is that, um, I have something called opportunities that I'll mention in just
그러니까 제 말은 저한테 기회가 있다는 거예요 잠시 후에 말씀드릴게요
I want that to be the input of this thing, this table.
그게 이 테이블의 입력값이 되길 원해요
And I want the output.
결과물도 필요해요
Whatever this returns, I want to hook that up to my data frame that I just defined right here.
이게 뭘 반환하든 데이터 프레임에 연결하고 싶어요 여기서 방금 정의한 거죠
Did you follow that the inputs are going to be this thing called opportunities that I'll speak about
입력이 기회라는 것이 된다는 것을 이해하셨나요? 잠시 후에 말씀드릴게요
And the whatever this get table returns, I want that to be hooked up to this table, this data frame
이 get 테이블이 반환하는 게 뭐든 그게 이 테이블에 연결되길 원해요 우리가 구성한 이 데이터
that we've constructed.
프레임에요
Hopefully that makes sense.
이해가 되면 좋겠네요
So what is this opportunities thing.
기회라는 게 뭔가요?
So this opportunities thing is a great state, which means it's a bit of information that I want the
이 기회란 건 훌륭한 상태예요 사용자 인터페이스가 기억해야 할 정보의
user interface to remember.
비트란 뜻이죠
And this great state is going to have in it something called initial opportunity, which is just going
이 훌륭한 상태는 초기 기회라는 것을 갖게 됩니다 여기서 하드 코딩하는
to be something I'm hard coding in here, which is going to be an opportunity for a deal called example
뭔가가 되겠죠 거래를 할 기회가 될 겁니다 예를 들어 설명 가격은 100달러죠
There's going to be a URL cnn.com.
URL cnn이 뜨겠죠 코무요
And that's going to be it.
그게 다예요
So let's run this and see what happens.
실행해 어떻게 되는지 보죠
We get a user interface.
get in 사용자 인터페이스가 있어요
We get this nice looking data frame which is like a table.
이렇게 멋진 데이터 프레임이 생겼어요 get 테이블 같은 거죠
And it has in it one row which has the thing that I just created with an example description, a price,
한 행에 제가 방금 만든 게 있어요 설명, 가격, 추정값,
an estimate, a discount and a URL.
디스카운트 URL
And that's, that's really the extent of it.
그게 전부인 것 같아요
Okay, so far, so good.
지금까진 좋아요
So let's keep going.
계속 가보죠
All right.
좋아요
Now the plot thickens.
얘기가 복잡해지네요
In this next cell, you can see I'm building on the user interface in each time.
다음 셀에서 사용자 인터페이스를 매번 구축하고 있는 걸 보실 수 있어요
And I love doing that.
전 그런 게 좋아요
That's one of the great things about it's a combination of the great thing about Jupyter Labs and also
그게 훌륭한 점 중 하나죠 유피터 랩의 훌륭한 점과 그래디오의 멋진 점이 이런
about Gradio is you can build in this way incrementally.
식으로 점진적으로 구축할 수 있다는 거예요
So I'm now going to create a new instance of an agent framework, a deal agent framework.
이제 에이전트 프레임워크의 새 인스턴스를 생성하겠습니다 딜 에이전트 프레임워크요
Uh, and uh, otherwise I'm going to, um, I guess we're going to hook up to this, I think, in a,
안 그러면 이 영상은 다음에 봐야 할 것 같네요
For now, uh, all I wanted to do was make it so that, uh, this would be hooked up.
지금은 이걸 연결하는 것만 신경 쓰고 있어요
We'd see it creating itself, we'd see some of the information, and I'd have it so that you can select
스스로 생성하는 걸 봤죠 일부 정보를 봤어요 기회를 선택할 수 있도록요
an opportunity, and it would call the messenger to alert about that opportunity.
그 기회에 대해 경고하기 위해 메신저를 호출하죠
Um, so what you can see down here is I've now got two different things hooked up using radios, standard
여기 아래를 보시면 두 개의 다른 것을 라디오로 연결했어요 표준 패턴이죠
This is the same as before.
아까랑 똑같네요
If you load it calls gettable, it passes in the opportunities and the outputs go in the frame.
gettable이라고 불러도 기회를 지나쳐 프레임에 출력되죠
If you select if you, if I'm um, I'm calling the select uh function on the data frame itself so that
선택하면.. 만약 데이터 프레임에 SELECT U 함수를 호출하면
if a selection is made it should call the function do select the inputs should again be the opportunity.
선택이 되면 함수를 호출하고 입력이 기회가 되겠죠.
There aren't any outputs.
결과물이 없어요
What does do select do.
무엇을 선택할까요?
It finds the index of what you've selected.
여러분이 선택한 것의 인덱스를 찾아요
And you specify that by having that as an argument right here, it looks up that opportunity from the
그걸 바로 여기 인수로 갖고 그걸 지정합니다 기회 목록에서 기회를 찾아내는
list of opportunities.
거죠
And it will then call the agent framework the planner the messenger and send an alert about that opportunity.
에이전트 프레임워크를 기획자 메신저로 호출해 그 기회에 대한 경고를 보내죠
All right.
좋아요
Seems reasonable.
합리적인 것 같네요
Let's run this.
이걸 실행하죠
When we run it, the first thing you'll see is that there's a lot of, um.
이걸 실행하면 제일 먼저 많은 게 보일 거예요
It was too fast.
너무 빨랐어요
If I go back, you'll see that it was printing.
되돌아가면 인쇄되고 있는 게 보일 거예요
Of course, our log output to the the command line here to to the output of the Jupyter lab.
물론 로그 출력은 명령줄로 유피터 랩의 출력으로 가죠
So we could see standard out.
표준형 밖을 볼 수 있죠
That's what I was grasping for.
그걸 노린 거예요
Then standard out is showing the log messages with the color system.
그 다음 표준 아웃은 색깔을 입힌 로그 메시지를 보여줘요
So we know what is doing what.
뭐가 뭘 하는지 알 수 있죠
Just as we wanted.
우리가 바라던 대로예요
And if we come over here it's showing our table with CNN.
여기 오면 CNN이 우리 테이블을 보여주고 있어요
And if I click on this I did just get a notification to show you believe it.
이걸 클릭하면 방금 알림이 나타났어요 get get get get
Hang on, I will press it again.
잠깐만요, 다시 눌러볼게요
Press and bang, I get a notification.
Get 버튼을 누르면 알림이 울리죠
Um, and so there you have it.
그렇게 된 거예요
We have now hooked up gradio to our agent framework at least so that it can notify us.
이제 그라디오와 우리 요원 프레임워크를 연결했으니 우리에게 통보할 수 있어요
So it's the beginnings of a user interface.
사용자 인터페이스의 시작이죠
It's the beginnings of something with the agent framework running behind the scenes.
에이전트 프레임워크가 막후에서 작동하는 것의 시작이죠
In the next video, we will move off the Jupyter Lab environment into the real code for the user interface.
다음 비디오에선 유피터 랩 환경에서 사용자 인터페이스를 위한 진짜 코드로 옮겨가죠
I'll see you then.
그때 봐요